Obsession can cause the unthinkable.
Perfume: The Story of a Murderer is a crime, fantasy,
drama film directed by Tom Tykwer.
Jean-Baptiste Grenouille, born in the stench of 18th century Paris, develops a superior
olfactory sense, which he uses to create the world's finest perfumes.
However, his work takes a dark turn as he tries to preserve
scents in the search for the ultimate perfume.
Jean-Baptiste Grenouille, played by Ben Whishaw.
Richis, played by Alan Rickman.
Laura, played by Rachel Hurd-Wood.
Giuseppe Baldini, played by Dustin Hoffman.
Narrator (voice), played by John Hurt.
The Plum Girl, played by Karoline Herfurth.
Perfume: The Story of a Murderer is a 2006 period psychological thriller film directed by Tom Tykwer, who cowrote the
screenplay with Andrew Birkin and Bernd Eichinger, based on the 1985 novel of the same name by Patrick Süskind.
The film stars Ben Whishaw, Alan Rickman, Rachel Hurd-Wood and Dustin Hoffman.
Set in 18th-century France, the film tells the story of Jean-Baptiste Grenouille
(Whishaw), an olfactory genius, and his homicidal quest for the perfect scent.
Producer Eichinger bought the film rights to Süskind's novel in 2000,
and began writing the screenplay together with Birkin.
Tykwer was selected as the director, and joined the two
in developing the screenplay in 2003.
Principal photography began July 12, 2005, and concluded October 16, 2005.
Filming took place in Spain, Germany and France.
The film was made on a budget of €50 million (est.
$60 million), making it one of the most expensive German films.
A co-production of Germany, France, Spain and the United States, Perfume was released September 14, 2006, in Germany by Constantin Film,
December 26, 2006, in the United Kingdom by Pathé Distribution, and December 27, 2006, in the United States by DreamWorks Pictures.
It grossed more than $135 million worldwide, of which
more than $53 million was made in Germany.
Critics gave the film mixed reviews.
The visual style and performances of Rickman and Whishaw were predominantly praised, while
the unevenness of the screenplay and casting of Hoffman were criticized.
The film explores themes of daughter, small town,
bad smell, prostitute, paris, france.
The tone is dark and emotional.